lyricsfreak.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy policy | LyricsFreak

**_Effective as of December 24, 2019_**

Lyricsfreak.com provides a platform, including a website available at  [www.LyricsFreak.com](http://www.lyricsfreak.com/), which makes available various services and content (the "Service"). "LyricsFreak", or "we" or "us" or “our” refers to LyricsFreakLyricsFreak.com and the LyricsFreak Corporate Family in this Privacy Policy (the "Policy"). The LyricsFreak Corporate Family means LyricsFreak's subsidiaries, parent companies, joint ventures and other corporate entities under common ownership and/or any of their agents, consultants, employees, officers and directors. 

We at LyricsFreak respect the privacy concerns of the users of this Service and have created this privacy policy to explain (1) what information we gather from you when you visit our Service, (2) how we may use such information, (3) your choices concerning how we may use such information and (4) the security measures we take to protect such information, (5) how you can contact us with any privacy-related questions. 

**Principles for Processing Personal Information**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information in compliance with applicable legislation. This compliance is consistent with our desire to keep you informed and to recognize and respect your privacy rights. We agree to observe the following principles when processing personal information:

  * Data will be processed fairly and in accordance with applicable law.
  * Data will be collected for specified, legitimate purposes and not processed further in ways incompatible with those purposes.
  * Data will be relevant to and not excessive for the purposes for which they are collected and used. For example, data may be rendered anonymous if deemed reasonable, feasible and appropriate, depending on the nature of the data and the risks associated with the intended uses.
  * Data subjects in the EU will be asked to provide their clear and unequivocal consent for the collection, processing and transfer of their personal data.
  * Data will be accurate and, where necessary kept up up-to-date. Reasonable, timely steps will be taken to rectify or delete personal information that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Data will be kept only as it is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected and processed. Those purposes shall be described in this Privacy Policy.
  * Data will be deleted or amended following a relevant request by the concerned data subject, should such notice comply with the applicable legislation each time.
  * Data will be processed in accordance with the individual's legal rights (as described in this Policy or as provided by law).
  * Appropriate technical, physical and organizational measures will be taken to prevent unauthorized access, unlawful processing and unauthorized or accidental loss, destruction or damage to data. In case of any such violation with respect to personal data, we will take appropriate steps to end the violation and determine liabilities in accordance with applicable law and will cooperate with the competent authorities.

_IMPORTANT:_ The Service contains links to other websites and services operated by third-parties that may allow you to purchase or download third-party products and content. Any information you provide to those third-party providers is subject to their own terms, data gathering practices and privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to these websites and services.   **We are not responsible for the privacy and security practices of those services and websites.** Before providing any information to a third-party provider you should review the applicable terms and policies.

**Notice to EU Residents**

This Policy is intended to provide adequate and consistent safeguards for the handling of personal information in accordance with Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data ("the Directive") and all the relevant transposing legislation of the Directive in the European Union/European Economic Area, the Swiss Federal Data Protection Act, as such laws may from time to time be amended and valid during the application of this Policy, the Privacy Shield, and any other privacy laws, regulations and principles concerning the collection, storage, use, transfer and other processing of personal data transferred from the European Economic Area or Switzerland to the United States including but not limited to the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC ("the General Data Protection Regulation") as of its entry into force on 25 May 2018.

**Information We Gather Automatically**

When you visit this Service, certain non-personally identifying information is recorded automatically by the standard operation of our Internet servers. Information such as the type of browser being used, its operating system, and your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address (a number that your Internet service provider assigns to your computer whenever you surf the Internet) is gathered in order to facilitate our online operations and to assure an efficient online experience for you. If you access our Service from a mobile or other device, we may collect information for that device (including operating system, browser, type of device) in order to facilitate our mobile operations and to assure an efficient mobile experience for you. We may use or share this information for security purposes, to generate group statistics about our user community, or as required by law.

Among the purposes for which we may use such generally non-personally identifying information is for identification purposes in the event of an emergency threatening life or property, or where proper legal process allows using such information. For instance, we may use your IP address or other automatically recorded information, in cooperation with your Internet provider, to attempt to identify you if it is necessary to contact you or to bring legal action against you because you are violating the Terms of Service for use for this Service, may be causing injury to or interference (intentionally or unintentionally) with our company's rights or property, or may be adversely affecting other users of this Service or anyone else who could be harmed by your activities.

**Personal Information You Provide To Us**

We may request personally identifying information from you in a variety of contexts. For example, you may provide such data to us if you submit lyrics via the “Submit Lyrics” tab at the top of this page. Additionally, when you ask for help from our Customer Support team, we will collect and store the contact information you give them (generally, your name and email address), information about your activity on our Services, the communications you have with the Customer Service team, and any information in those communications in order to provide support.

In such cases, the personally identifying information we request may include your name, email address, mailing address and zip code, and phone number (collectively, "Personal Information"). In addition, we may collect other non-personally identifying information such as your gender, country of residence, language preference, and other information regarding your interaction with our Service such as your search and viewing habits, preferences and other customized activities in which you participate. Of course, you never have to answer any of the questions we ask you (nor choose to view any content or otherwise interact with our Service), but refusal to do so may limit the services we can offer or provide to you.

**How May Your Personal Information Be Used**

Within LyricsFreak

When you use the Service, we will use the Personal Information you provide for customer service. LyricsFreak keeps track of the websites and pages you visit within the Service, what features and content you use and how frequently. This information may be used by LyricsFreak to maintain and improve the content, design, usability, and quality of the Service; to improve your user experience; to generate and provide statistics regarding use of the Service; to deliver customized content and advertising within the Service to users whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area, and to develop new products and services. Your Personal Information may be stored on the LyricsFreak cloud in order to provide interoperability of the Service among your devices.

We may have links to third-party-operated sites that sell or license certain music, videos, or other goods mentioned, provided, or promoted on LyricsFreak. Such third-party sites are not operated or controlled by LyricsFreak, and any transactions that you may enter into with such sites will be subject to the privacy and security practices of the merchant with which you are transacting. **LyricsFreak is not responsible for the privacy and security practices of sites not in our immediate control.**

We may use your Personal Information and other non-personally identifying information we collect to update you about our services or to contact you about exciting offers of new services that we believe may be of interest to you. You always have the option to receive fewer or no communications in the future from us by opting-out. You may opt-out by (a) following the instructions included in the specific communication you no longer wish to receive or (b) sending an email to privacy@LyricsFreak.com and explaining how you would like to modify your preferences.

Finally, without any specific approval from you, we may develop general aggregate data (i.e., data that cannot be used to identify specific individuals) about our user community that is partly based on information about you and your interactions with LyricsFreak. For example, hypothetically, you might be one of 1,000,000 customers between the ages of 25 and 35. We may share such aggregate statistics with other companies in the LyricsFreak Corporate Family without your consent.

Contest Sponsors

When you give Personal Information to LyricsFreak in connection with a contest, we may share that data (together with non-personally identifying information you may provide) with the sponsor(s) of such contest. By entering a contest, you are allowing such sponsor(s) to use such Personal Information and to contact you in connection with the contest and in accordance with their own privacy policies.

Outside LyricsFreak

When you give Personal Information to LyricsFreak, we may ask you to allow us to share that data (together with non-personally identifying information you may provide) with our promotional partners and third-party advertisers. In such instances, our general practice is to ask you to "opt-in" to share such data and information. However, in some instances, we may ask you to "opt-out" from sharing such data and information with a given promotional partner or third-party advertiser in connection with a specific promotion or contests. If you prefer, you may give us blanket permission to share your Personal Information with all of our promotional partners and third-party advertisers. Conversely, you may also choose not to allow us to share your Personal Information with any other companies outside LyricsFreak.

If you consent to share your Personal Information with our promotional partners and third-party advertisers, you are allowing such parties to use such Personal Information and to contact you in accordance with their own privacy policies. You have the option to change your mind and to stop us from further sharing your Personal Information with our promotional partners and third-party advertisers by contacting privacy@LyricsFreak.com and explaining how you would like to modify your preferences. If you wish to limit or discontinue receiving further communications from a promotional partner or third-party advertiser, please contact that company directly in the manner indicated in its own communications with you.

Without any specific approval from you, LyricsFreak may develop general aggregate data (i.e., data that cannot be used to identify specific individuals) about you that is partly based on information about you and your transactions us. We may share such aggregate statistics with promotional partners and third-party advertisers without your consent.

Finally, we may use your Personal Information in connection with third-party advertisers who serve ads to you while visiting an LyricsFreak Service. These third-party advertisers may use your Personal Information (not including any personally identifying information you may provide) in order to generate advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like to know more about this practice and to obtain information about how third-party advertisers use your Personal Information to select advertisements please click [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/).

Service Providers

We may employ third-party companies to provide customer support, perform website-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the website's features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. These third-parties may have access to your personal information to the extent required to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Contest Winners

As further explained in our contest rules, by entering into a contest, you grant us the right to disclose name, biographical information, pictures/portraits, video images, likenesses and/or voice to the general public if you are a contest winner.

For Legal Enforcement Purposes

We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information as required by law or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against you if you are violating the Terms of Service for this Service or may be causing injury to or interference (intentionally or unintentionally) with our company's rights or property, other users of this Service or anyone else who could be harmed by your activities. Additionally, LyricsFreak cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of LyricsFreak or a third-party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, an illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

As an Asset of LyricsFreak

If LyricsFreak becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale or transfer of some or all of its assets, your information will be transferred to the acquiring entity. In such a situation, you will be provided with notice that a transfer of your information is imminent, and you will be given an opportunity to opt-out of the transfer of your information.

**Do Not Sell My Personal Information**

California law requires that we maintain a separate webpage that allows you to opt out of the sale of your personal information, which can be accessed by clicking the link below:

**How Can You Correct or Review Your Personal Information?**

You can access, review, update and correct Personal Information you have provided us by sending us an email at privacy@LyricsFreak.com and explaining how you would like to modify your information.

If any information is inaccurate or incomplete, you may request that the data be amended. It is your responsibility to provide us with accurate personal information about yourself and to inform us of any changes. (e.g. new home address or change of name).

You also have the right to request the deletion of your personal data for any reason by emailing privacy@LyricsFreak.com. If you demonstrate that the purpose for which the data is being processed is no longer legal or appropriate, the data will be deleted, unless the applicable law requires otherwise. 

**Safeguarding Your Personal Information**

Information Security 

To safeguard against unauthorized access to Personal Information by third-parties, all electronic Personal Information held by LyricsFreak is maintained on systems that are protected by up-to-date secure network architectures that contain firewalls and intrusion detection devices. The data saved in servers is "backed up" (i.e. the data are recorded on separate media) to avoid the consequences of any inadvertent erasure, destruction or loss otherwise. The servers are stored in facilities with high security, access restricted to unauthorized personnel, fire detection and response systems.

Physical and Administrative Security

We employ reasonable physical and administrative safeguards to protect your Personal Information. While we will use such efforts, we cannot and will not insure the security of your information. Accordingly, we assume no liability for any disclosure of data due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access or other acts of third-parties, or acts or omissions beyond our reasonable control.

**For Parents Concerning the Privacy of Information on Their Children**

Children under 13 are not allowed to use LyricsFreak. If you are based in the EEA you may only use LyricsFreak if you are over the age at which you can provide consent to data processing under the laws of your country or if verifiable parental consent for your use of LyricsFreak has been provided to us. If you are a parent and you learn that your child is using LyricsFreak and you don't want them to,  [please](mailto:privacy@LyricsMode.com) contact us at privacy@LyricsFreak.com. 

**International Operations and Transfers Out of Switzerland and the EEA**

LyricsFreak is a worldwide service. By using LyricsFreak, you authorize us to transfer and store your information outside your home country, including in the United States, for the purposes described in this policy. The privacy protections and the rights of authorities to access your information in these countries may not be the same as in your home country.

We take additional measures when information is transferred from the European Economic Area (EEA). This includes having standard clauses approved by the European Commission in our contracts with parties that receive information outside the EEA. We also rely on European Commission adequacy decisions about certain countries, as applicable, for data transfers to countries outside the EEA.

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is a small text file that an Internet Service can place on your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make using this Service easier by, among other things, saving your passwords and preferences for you, keeping track of your shopping cart when you visit an online store or other similar purposes, and to help identify you whenever you return to our Service, so you do not need to reenter your identification information. Most Internet browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. However, you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to alert you when a cookie is being sent (note: you may need to consult your browser's "Help" area for instructions on how to do that). If you choose to disable your cookies setting or refuse to accept a cookie, some parts of this Service will not function properly or may perform considerably slower. For example, without cookies, you will not be able to set personalized preferences or you may have difficulty loading lyrics. Some of our web pages may contain electronic images (called "Clear GIFs", "Single-Pixel GIFs", or "Web Beacons") that allow us to count page views or to access cookies. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a Clear GIF. Typically, though, Clear GIFs are very small (1-by-1 pixel size) files. They are often invisible on a web page, but their presence can be detected within many Internet browsers by setting your browser to view web page "sources". Clear GIFs are so small in order not to use valuable space on the computer screen that is better used to display helpful content. We may also include Clear GIFs in our email products in order to determine information about the opening and reading of such emails. In addition, some advertising networks that serve ads on our web Service may occasionally use Clear GIFs within banner advertisements. Clear GIFs set by LyricsFreak generally are not used to collect, gather, monitor, or share Personal Information about our users, though they can be used in conjunction with cookies to record particular actions. We use Clear GIFs primarily to compile aggregated, anonymous statistics about web Service or email product usage.

Some of the advertisements and other services that appear on our Service are delivered to you by Internet advertising companies. These companies utilize certain technologies including cookies to deliver advertisements and marketing messages and to collect anonymous information about your visit to our sites and other web sites. If you would like more information about this practice or to opt out of having this information used by companies that are part of the Network Advertising Initiative to provide targeted ads, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Links to Other Sites**

We do not endorse and are not responsible for the content or practices of web sites operated by companies outside of LyricsFreak that may be linked to this Service. You should not assume that their privacy policies or practices are the same as those followed by our company or by other LyricsFreak companies. Visitors to any such web sites should refer to their respective privacy policies and practices.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or complaints about our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at 268 Bush Street, #3044, San Francisco, CA 94104 or privacy@LyricsFreak.com. When we receive such inquiries about our Privacy Policy, we will use the Personal Information (such as your email address) only to respond to your question or comment. However, if your question raises one or more issues that affect our promotional partners, we may also share your question with them in order to provide a response. You may request access to any Personal Information maintained on you by LyricsFreak at any time by emailing privacy@LyricsFreak.com.

**Obligations to Data Protection Authorities**

We will respond diligently and appropriately to requests from DPAs about this Policy or compliance with applicable data protection privacy laws and regulations. We will, upon request, provide DPAs with names and contact details of the individuals designated to handle this process. With regard to transfers of Personal Information, we will (i) cooperate with inquiries from the DPA responsible for the entity exporting the data and (ii) respect its decisions, consistent with applicable law and due process rights. With regard to transfers of data to third-parties, we will comply with DPAs' decisions relating to it and cooperate with all DPAs in accordance with applicable legislation.

**Changes in This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time, so we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time-to-time. Any information that is collected is subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time such information is collected. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, or any subsequent privacy policies, we will notify you of such changes by posting them here or on the home page of our website and we will indicate when such changes will become effective. 

**Acceptance of This Privacy Policy**

By using this Service, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Information by LyricsFreak in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
